#### CISHAHAYO SONGA Achille

Junior Software Engineer

In the pursuit of making an impact, we forget the contribution our small actions make to big things. I had been working on small projects since 2018 and learnt a lot since then. Experienced in software development lifecycle, and project management. I make sure that my project gets everything possible to make it a success. I am a great team player, skilled in working in cross-cultural teams and competent communicator, respecting my deadlines.

Email: songachillethe1her@gmail.com

Linkedin: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/achillesonga">https://linkedin.com/in/achillesonga</a>

**Github**: <a href="https://github.com/songa1">https://github.com/songa1</a> **Portfolio**: <a href="https://achillesonga.com">https://achillesonga.com</a>

**Phone**: +250780630465

**Location**: Kicukiro, Kigali, Rwanda

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Web and mobile application design and development, Project Management, Software development lifecycle

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Technical Team Lead**

Andela Rwanda, Kigali February 2022 – Present

#### Responsibilities:

1. Supervised and lead a team of 13 junior software engineers during the Andela Technical Leadership Program boot camp, while they develop their personal websites.

## Front-End Developer Intern

AC Group Rwanda, Kigali April 2021-July 2021

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Utilized expertize on PERN stack to create and optimize web pages performance.
- 2. Enhanced the application's features to effectively fix the bugs and optimize the overall performance, reliability and efficiency.
- 3. Utilized software engineering expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle to boost business efficiency.

### Full stack Software developer / Team Lead

Techinika Rwanda, Kigali May 2021 – Present

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Leading the team of three software developers in the development and maintenance of our clients' products.
- 2. Documenting the supported systems and applications to effectively train the new and existing team members.
- 3. Developing applications and websites along with the team as requested by a customer.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Apache HTTP server, React JS, React Native, Next JS, Vanilla Javascript, Javascript(Node JS), Java, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Linux, Github, C

#### **CERTIFICATES**

## Certified Software Engineer from ATLP (July 2021)

Andela Technical Leadership Program

# Certificate of a Participating and winning in a debate competition (2021)

IPRC Kigali Gavel Club

## Certificate on Python I and II (2018)

Progate.com – kLab and Progate developer challenge

#### **COURSES AND TRAINING**

## Software Engineering Training (October 2020 – July 2021)

A trainee in Andela ATLP.

## API development with Django training (2018)

One week hackaton at kLab

## **EDUCATION**

## Information Technology (March 2021-Present)

A student at IPRC Kigali (Rwanda Polytechnic)

## Computer Networking (January 2017 - November 2019)

IPRC Kigali Technical Secondary School

## **LANGUAGES**

Language	Speak	Write	Read
English	Very good	Very good	Very good
Kinyarwanda	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent
French	Not good	Good	Good

I, hereby confirm that the information provided above is the true, and if anything is found to be wrong, I am accepting to be held responsible for it.

CISHAHAYO SONGA Achille.